[rooster crowing]
[wind blowing, leaves rustling]
[phone ringing]
Hello?
[woman] Hello? Modesta?
Who's calling?
[man] All right, I'll make it work, madam.
Dencio, we're back in business.
Cake, you seen Jo?
Here, Director.
The network wants Dencio back.
Yes, but I'm sure we shot Dencio.
He's dead.
Who wants to see this show canceled?
-No one.
-[all] No!
Okay, then how do we bring him back
from the dead?
Perhaps it's a nightmare, or he's a ghost,
reincarnation?
It's an action series, all right,
not a fantasy.
Jo, you're the writer.
-Think about it.
-Right, at this point, I don't know.
-Spirits, maybe?
-Spirits is a little far out.
-[woman] Take the glass.
-Excuse me, director.
What if there's a twin?
[gulps]
Twins. Case closed!
Make up for Dencio.
[all cheering]
God damn it, Matti!
If you didn't pack that bag,
I'm gonna fucking kill you!
Mom, wtf I told you I brought it.
You reminded me, like, 500 times.
-Really?
-Yes. Five hundred times.
-500?
-Yes. I counted.
-Spare me the math.
-Shut up.
And will you stop sounding so smart.
You're such a little shit!
Hey, are you here to drive us?
Ma'am Paz De Los Santos?
Don't call me ma'am.
-I'm not that old.
-Let me take that, ma'am.
-Get in the car.
-I've got this.
-Be careful.
-Hey, move along.
Time's up.
Don't call me ma'am. [sarcastically]
Shit. Is this true?
Yes. Your dad's picking her up
from the pier.
I need to get to set now.
I'll call you later, mom.
Hello, dear?
[sighs]
The buried have arisen.
Who?
The one who went AWOL.
-They've returned.
-Your natural mother?
Our lady of eternal absence?
OMG.
The former starlet is making a comeback?
[weather forecast on radio]
This is fucking surreal.
Welcome home!
You're fucking weird, Mom.
[both chuckle]
Well, that workshop's another thing.
They have so many requirements, they've
even asked for a sequence treatment.
At least now my visa's ready.
I think you've got this, girl!
You revived a dead body, didn't you?
Your bad!
Eighteen sequences, on the spot.
-I know you can--
-Girl.
We're talking about America.
Well, you never know,
they might hire you when you're there,
Miss Shonda Rhimes!
She might hire you, girl, think on that.
But wait…
Can you really leave all this behind?
All this?
Yeah.
-Yeah.
-Yeah!
I'm ready to.
[ship horn blowing]
Wake up, Matias. Wake up.
What?
Just smell that.
Smell it. It's… [inhales deeply]
-…pure ocean air.
-[coughs]
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah. The ocean, yeah.
-Here.
-Thanks.
It's just so weird to be back, you know?
I'm sure they're all excited to see us.
Really?
I was famous, you know?
Mm-hmm.
I was!
Once upon a time, I was
Manila's up and coming dramatic star.
[chuckles]
Did you ever arrive?
Watch it, or I'll send you overboard.
I think we're here.
[ship horn blowing]
THIS, THAT AND EVERYTHING IN BETWEEN
-Matti, watch the bag!
-Mom, they're not gonna run away.
[people chattering]
Rene!
Rene?
Is that you? Paz?
I don't believe it.
-Can you put those in the back?
-Who? Who's that?
Still your car?
You should know I'm not the kind of guy
who just throws broken things away.
Who's this?
My son.
-Welcome. Welcome. Welcome.
-Hi
-Make yourself at home.
-Thanks.
-Hurry up.
-Hop in.
[Paz] Thank you.
Be careful, Matti.
[groans]
-[Paz] Does everything fit?
-Uh-huh.
Let's go.
Are you okay, Matti?
Yeah. Yeah.
Is the box up there?
Yeah.
There.
This old house waited for you.
I had Claro clean the house.
You remember our old helper?
They were useless.
Jo uses your old room when she's here,
but she hardly ever comes home.
I've prepared your father's room.
Oh…
who have you brought with you?
This is my youngest, Matti.
[Bes] Wow,
so handsome.
He looks like a celebrity.
Say hello to Manang.
He's just like his mother.
My God. Just give her a kiss.
Come on, come through here.
[Matti playing guitar]
[Paz] Matias!
Cut it out!
[guitar stops]
[cell phone ringing]
Dad.
[Rene] Jo, darling, come home, please.
Your mom wants to see you.
It's…
Dad, I have a lot of work here.
Sweetheart, family comes first.
You can't just work all the time.
You haven't been here for a while.
Please come home.
You know, it's been a while
since I've seen you--
-[groans softly]
-What happened? Everything all right, Jo?
Let me get back to you.
-At least think--
-Shit!
[Jo] It's just one thing after another.
Okay…
so tell me, let's look at that.
Just remember, you're in a safe space.
This workshop,
it's great. I'm not complaining.
I mean, this is my chance to…
to actually make a better life for myself.
It's just that I wonder now that
it's getting closer to being a reality,
if this is the right thing for me to do,
'cause…
'cause I feel, I don't know,
I feel like there's something missing.
I know this is a great move
and it could change my life, but…
I feel like…
I feel like there's
something I need to do first.
Are we talking mostly about
the trip right now, or…
is there something else bothering you?
I heard Paz is here.
[voice shaking]
My God!
She's back.
Just when I'm finally moving on
with my life,
I have to rip open wounds.
And my father wants me to be there at home
as if it's all okay now,
it's all fine.
I mean, now, I don't know this person.
She never cared for me.
That's what they don't understand.
That it took a lot for me
to get to this point.
Sure, family, it's important,
but tell me how you would react
if this was your family.
[sighs]
Then don't go.
Don't go.
You have your own life right now.
I have my own life.
It's your choice.
Remember what we talked about?
Personal boundaries.
Boundaries. Yes.
It's not a selfish thing to do, Jo.
Okay.
Boundaries.
Yes.
Here…
your other hand.
Let's breathe.
Okay,
deep inhale.
-[inhales deeply]
-Two, three, four.
Hold and exhale.
-[exhales deeply]
-Two, three, four.
Hold.
It's your choice.
It's my choice.
-It's my choice.
-Another one. Inhale.
-[inhales deeply]
-Two, three, four.
Hold…
[ship horn blowing]
[yelps] Damn it!
-[chuckles]
-Pain in the ass.
[Rene] It's gone now.
What are you laughing about?
Such a waste.
Don't you get bored, Renato?
Not at all.
I don't think there's anything boring
about living peacefully.
-Can I ask you a question?
-Hmm.
What does that place have, that we don't?
Where is that?
America.
We've got TV here,
the movies and shows are no different.
What the fuck is your point, Renato?
Why did you have to go so far away?
Most things can be fixed, right?
Whether it's a big thing or a small thing,
you try and fix it
instead of just up and leaving.
That hurt me, you know, and Jo too.
You don't get me, I see that.
Well, you should have explained yourself
to me before you ran away.
I couldn't do that, for you.
Do you think you can explain yourself now?
[Paz] Shit.
It's stuck.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit!
Fuck!
[exhales]
[Jo] Shit, shit, shit, shit!
[groans softly]
[dog marking]
[both screaming]
Is that… Joanne?
Joanne!
-[Jo screams]
-[coughing]
Joanne?
Joanne, it's me!
Why didn't you tell me you were coming?
-Joanne?
-I'm peeing!
Joanne, have you met your brother?
-Joanne?
-Brother?
Joanne, come out!
Joanne!
I'm so happy.
My two, full grown children together.
-Matti, meet your sister Joanne.
-It's Jo.
-Joanne, meet Matti.
-Jo.
Gosh, look at you.
You're all grown up.
-The last time I saw you…
-I was ten.
Well, look at her, will you?
You look so much like each other.
We look so similar, don't you think?
Except for the nose.
And looks like you haven't slept
in years…
and you could do more carbs,
you know, just, you know,
for the meat of it.
Hey, how about you can
sleep in my bedroom?
-We could chit chat.
-Your bedroom?
Yes, my bedroom.
It's huge, the bed's enormous.
Or maybe you want wine.
You want wine?
-Or maybe a joint? All right, let's do it.
-I'm tired.
I'm tired.
Let's talk about my life in New York!
Joanne!
Hey, who the hell is that?
You'll give a heart attack.
What time is it?
Can I stay here?
She's taken my room.
I'm glad you came home.
Wait there.
I need to pee.
How long will they stay?
I don't know.
Nobody knows.
[sighs softly]
Why?
She's your mother.
[Rene] You're a scoundrel.
I bet you're just after my money,
aren't you?
You think they still recognize me?
Why are they all staring?
Because you look like a bug lady.
Stop it! What's this?
Salted egg. Can you believe it?
-Yeah.
-Yeah. That's nice.
I missed these.
They're so good.
This is amazing.
Hey, you know, this is so Philippines.
-Are you hot now?
-Look, look, look.
Can I try this on?
Of course, ma'am.
-Do you think this works for me?
-Yeah, it looks nice. It looks very nice.
I'm not sure.
Just buy it. Come on.
It's Aunt Abby.
-Quick. Thanks.
-Rude.
-[Rene] Be careful.
-Paz!
Careful with the eggs,
I don't wanna break them.
-Is that you, Paz?
-Okay. Let's go.
Drive!
[Bes] Jo!
Tilapia. It was just caught.
-Mom, look at that.
-Yeah.
Rene, we can make ceviche with this.
[Rene] Sweetheart.
How long have you been here?
Since morning, Dad.
Good girl.
Have you had the pleasure
of meeting your brother?
I wonder if he was a premature baby…
because he acts like…
he's not fully grown.
I gotta go get something.
Well, Paz, I said we'd bump
into that old lady eventually, right?
She's like a dog with a bone.
She doesn't miss a thing.
Wait…
did you only buy fruit and vegetables?
No.
Here we go.
Rice. Look. Good job. There.
Now, that'll be perfect.
Now, I'll get that fish cooked
and serve it with the leftover rice.
And then I'll do that…
Do what?
Start making sense, will you?
Can you be more clear?
-I am being clear.
-[Bes screams outside]
It's Matti!
Huh?
[Bes] Hey!
Hey, Matti!
Matti!
You don't know how to swim.
Matti, like this.
Look at me! Rene!
-Matti!
My God!
[panting]
[distant voices]
Jo. Hey, wait!
Matti!
[coughing]
[Paz] My God! Matti!
Matti!
What the fuck were you thinking?
You can't swim.
You could have drowned out there!
You could have died out there! Stupid!
[Rene] Hey, relax, calm down.
You never listen to me.
If you'd listened to me,
you can't fucking swim! Goddamn it!
-You were told.
-[Rene] Hey, calm down!
He'll be all right on my watch.
What the hell? He could have died!
I'll give him swimming lessons.
I can't believe you all.
Damn you! Modesta,
I don't want to deal with my child!
Now, come on.
-You!
-Stop that!
-What's the matter with you?
-[Bes] That's enough now.
-Fuck!
-That's enough.
[on radio] I just need to buy medicine
for my mom.
She's been sick for a long time.
I have no other way of earning money.
Have pity on me.
Manang, don't you get sick
of these radio dramas?
Please, please, have mercy on our port.
[phone ringing]
Darling. Jo. Sweetheart, it's your phone.
-Mom?
-Here.
That's how she addresses you?
Mmm.
[counsellor] Hi. Where are you?
San Rafael.
You went there. If you told me,
I would've come with you.
And why would you come here?
Moral support.
Are you okay?
Trying.
[Paz] Darling, the food's getting cold.
I gotta go.
Jo.
You-hoo!
Maria Paz?
Maria Paz Del La Santos?
Paz, do you think that
you're going to be here for good?
Because, if you're here for good,
we should have a get together.
A party?
No, I'm too old.
Just a simple one.
Who would be there?
Relatives.
No.
Why not?
All right. Just your brother then.
And you could invite your friends
from showbiz, from the old days.
Please invite them, especially…
I see her all the time on the television.
You were always together.
She's still very famous these days.
[whispers] Stella.
Stella, yes. Mmm.
Mmm.
I feel nervous all of a sudden.
You know what?
If your mother didn't go to the States,
she would have become a big star,
because way back then,
she acted with Cherie Hill…
-Mmm.
-with Gretchen, Alice Dixon,
and the biggest star around,
Stella Guevara.
Very nice.
Where did you find this kid?
I'm not filling you in now, aunt,
maybe next time.
-I hate it here, Mom.
-Do you hear what you're saying?
Matti!
[Paz] Stop it.
Why did you bring me here?
I don't belong here.
[Paz] What are you doing?
You're gonna live off the streets?
-[Matti groans]
-Oh, be quiet!
I don't belong here.
Why did you bring me here?
What happened to you there?
Matti!
What? What are you gonna do?
You'll be on the street.
-You have nothing to go back…
-Don't touch me!
We have nothing to go back to there.
Maybe you, but not me!
Why does it always have to be your way?
You think your father will save you?
Your dad's a coward.
Yes, he wants nothing to do with you.
-[Matti grunts]
-Come here. Stop it, Matti!
Matti, stop!
Stop it!
Stop! Stop!
[Matti crying]
I'm here. I'm here for you.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay,
-it's okay, it's okay.
-[Matti sobbing]
And who's this?
Your partner in the movie?
Yes, Kenneth. Look at his bulge.
Looks like a child's arm.
They used to wrap it up in a stocking.
That's how it was done.
My goodness.
Look,
this is old.
What's this doing out here?
You look, you're so young there.
Look, there's Joanne.
Yeah, where was that?
It was in La Union.
[Bes] Jo, darling.
Joanne, come look.
Look.
Modesta when she was younger.
And look at you.
We have no pictures together.
I'm always with Nono and Nana.
You were never there.
See.
-Will I bring this out?
-Mm.
Who do you think took the pictures?
[sneezes]
Modesta, you need to clean in here.
Time to sing.
You ready for karaoke?
What?
-What is that?
-Hey, Paz.
-Rene! Whose idea was this?
-What?
-I thought you wanted some sound.
-Music.
This is loud noise. Just loud noise.
It's all the same, right?
This is hard to wrangle.
All right, boys, lets…
You're such a ridiculous man.
Sounds, all right, sounds!
This is a terrible idea!
Come on, boys, put it here.
What have I forgotten?
Ice! Ice!
You already did that.
Well, they already got ice.
It's done.
What else is there?
Everyone here! They've arrived.
-[music playing]
-[indistinct chatter]
[Paz] Your dad's a coward!
Goddamn!
Matti.
[music continues]
[remembering Paz's conversation]
Your dad's a coward.
He's a coward. A coward.
[Rene] Come here! Hey, come out!
Everyone, they're here! Hey, hey!
Who the fuck are these people?
[breathing heavily]
Matti?
-[coughing]
-Matti, are you smoking?
-Is that my weed?
-One second.
Matti, get dressed now.
They're coming.
Don't cover it, the skin will get soggy.
-My God.
-This was a simple get together.
This is simple, darling.
Do you want some crispy lechon skin?
There's some here.
I'm fine, thank you.
Are you on one of those diets again?
You might get cancer.
♪ Pink light, little shoes ♪
♪ We can be whoever we choose ♪
♪ Candy sky, in your dreams ♪
♪ Everything's better than what it seems ♪
[continues singing karaoke]
Yuck!
What are you doing?
-This wine's spoiled.
-No, no, no, no. Don't do this.
This wine is rank.
Show me.
There. You see?
-This is fine.
-What do you mean, fine?
Hey…
-what's happening here?
-It's fine.
Aunt Abby, the wine is rank.
Rank? It's not rank.
It's disgusting.
[man] Hello?
Yes, in here.
Hi.
-Hi.
Is Jo here?
My Joanne?
Yeah, I'm Migs. I'm a friend of Jo's.
Sorry, what?
Migs?
You're here for the party?
I'm just visiting.
I'm not here for the party. I'm sorry.
-Maybe I'll just…
-No, no, no. I'll, I'll take you to her.
Come with me.
[Paz] Joanne?
You have a visitor.
Joanne?
-Miguel, right?
-Shit!
Joanne?
-Your friend Miguel is here.
-In the shower!
Are you friends from work?
Paz!
Pipo just arrived.
Just keep knocking.
Thank you.
[Migs] Jo. [knock on door]
Jo--
I said not to come over!
-My God!
-What?
And what?
How did you find this place,
and who saw you?
My God!
What, it was just your mother.
You're not supposed to be here.
Maria Paz!
-I thought you weren't coming.
-Paz!
-My God, look who's here.
-Hi.
You look beautiful.
-How did you know?
-I heard from Pipo.
-Look at that face. The skin is amazing.
-Thank you.
-Hi, Pipo!
-My God, Modesta.
I can't believe how beautiful you are.
-Welcome!
-Abby.
It's Aunt Abby.
-Hello, aunty.
-You're here.
Hi.
You're still so beautiful.
You're still so beautiful!
Thank you.
No thanks.
My taste buds have been off lately.
I don't know. I think it's the water.
What if your diet's causing too much
acid to build up in your gut?
-Are you sure you're okay?
-Yeah.
My doctor in New York
said I'm as healthy as a 30s something.
[all chuckle]
[all] Cheers!
You're amazing.
I just wanted to see you
to see if you were fine.
What have you heard from Paz?
She say anything?
She asked how I knew you.
I said we were friends. It's no big deal.
Big deal.
Hello? Are you stupid?
Boundaries, remember? Boundaries!
God.
Come on, relax.
-You seem so--
-I can't relax.
I can't.
[karaoke singing in the background]
Okay, I'll go home.
-You'll have to give me the recipe.
-Use coffee, sometimes
chocolate to make it deeper.
Yeah, right.
It's so good.
Lord. Lord!
Please forgive those who do not know
how to say "Thank you"
before eating.
-[chuckles]
-Amen.
[all] Amen.
Sorry, Aunt Abby.
-I left my manners in Manila.
-Okay.
[moaning]
[karaoke continues]
Tell me, how's the business
of show that I left behind?
-This one's finished for play now.
-Oh, stop.
Hey, wait, wait.
You do plays now?
Yeah. She's won so many awards.
-No!
-I have.
-Really?
-Good for her.
Long day's journey into night.
That play would be tiring.
It was tiring,
but, you know, it was exhilarating.
That's what all the reviewers said.
It was so exciting, but I was also, like,
nervous, like I was on drugs.
You should know.
But seriously, I'm very,
very happy for you, friend.
But personally, I think, you know,
theater was never for me.
-It's just--
-You were in New York.
Don't get me wrong.
I just feel, it's a chore.
You're doing the same thing
over and over again.
It's quite demeaning, you know.
-No offense to you, of course.
-None taken.
-That's just me.
-Pipo.
I hear your last movie was very good.
When can I--
It's a Netflix show, aunt.
Netflick? What theater is that?
You can download it, aunt.
My brother!
This is Netflix!
Why do I never know these things?
Because you were gone.
Well, you could have messaged me.
[laughter]
There you are.
Hi. Grandma Abby.
Not Grandma, auntie.
Hey. You're getting married
sooner or later?
I'm getting old.
Jo, oh my God,
you're so pretty.
This one's looking for a grandchild.
-This is grown up Jo.
-Joking
Uncle.
-Hi.
-Sit down, baby.
Sit there.
Leave that seat for Matti.
Where's your…
There he is.
-Joanne, introduce--
-My friend, everyone.
Hello.
-Hi.
-[Paz] Have a seat.
Stay there across from Joanne.
Des, can you please call Matti?
You need to eat. Eat.
I can't get over it.
I can't stop looking at you.
You've grown, Jo.
Well, I was much slimmer than her
when I was younger, right?
But I had boobs.
Oh, you idiot. That's not what I'm saying.
The last time I saw her,
she was just a kid,
and now you're a full grown woman.
I heard you're writing for TV.
That's right.
She's the head writer
of the highest-rating show now.
-Oh.
-Oh, my God.
That's another family matter I missed.
Tell me, how's work?
It's all fine, thanks.
Well, it pays the bills.
Though it feels
like you're on a treadmill.
You keep on running, but you don't
move forward, that sort of thing.
Are you happy?
Mmm.
-Yeah.
-Hey, Paz, change of topic.
I'd like to know, why have you come back?
[Stella] Yeah.
Oh, finally! There you are!
Everyone, I'd like you to meet my son.
This is Matti.
Matti, say hello to everyone.
-Hi, everyone.
-[Paz] This is my brother.
He's your Uncle Pipo.
-Hey.
-You know, I always wanted a gay uncle.
-[Pipo laughs]
-[mouthing]
-[Stella] Uncle Pipo.
-Hi.
-Hi, Grandma.
-Hi!
Handsome. He's so handsome.
-And that's Miguel.
-Migs.
Oh, hey, what's up?
You know, man, I really like your style.
It reminds me of, um…
Uh…
Uhhh…
-Everything good?
-Hup.
-Are you here with Uncle Pipo?
-Uh…
No. He's your, uh, sister's--
-My friend. My friend.
-Oh!
Well, welcome to the family.
-And you're?
-Stella.
-[yelling] Stella!
-Oh!
[Stella laughs]
You know, you're the one
my mom talks shit about all the time.
[Stella] Oh, well, you're very handsome.
Oh. This is your favorite. Fried chicken.
Matt, eat your fried chicken
that…has cooked for you.
It's your favorite, right?
Paz, this one's just like you were.
[Pipo] I agree. He's just like you.
[all cheering, singing]
Paz, I didn't hear your answer earlier.
What was your question?
Why did you suddenly come back?
Oh. Oh, boredom, you know.
New York can be actually quite boring.
After having lived there
for 15, 20 years…
Twenty seven. Twenty seven.
[Paz] Oh, there you go.
Twenty-seven stressful years.
It wasn't easy.
So, did you work there?
Yeah, I did. I…independent films.
-Oh.
-Actually I'm in the Screen Actors Guild.
[all] Ooh.
How is work?
Oh, let's not bother with the details,
but they loved my acting for sure.
[Stella] Whoa.
-[Paz] Hmm.
-What role did you play?
An Asian woman…
-who's fierce and crazy.
-Ah, perfect.
-You must have been great.
-I was.
-She was bad.
-[Tita Abby] Oh.
I was not.
She attacked the director,
accused him of being racist,
which, in fact, he was,
and smashed his head in
with a metal suitcase.
[laughs]
He had to be taken to the hospital after.
[Tita Abby] Uh…
Paz, I take it you know
who the father is, don't you?
[Rene] Not guilty.
-Rene.
-[cell phone ringing]
-[Stella] Hi!
-Oh, hi!
-[Stella] How are you? Long time no see.
-Hi. Welcome.
-Great to see you.
-[Jo] Excuse me.
Are you… Uh…
-Yes…
-Hey. Good news.
-Your talent fee's been transferred.
-[sighs]
Yeah. Check your balance.
You're all set to fly.
[chuckles]
Thank you. Thank you.
Okay. Bye.
[Skype ringtone]
-Hi, Ben.
-[Ben] What's up, Jo?
-I'm in.
-Ah, that's awesome news.
Just in time.
I was talking to Mike the other day
and he thinks your pitch has promise.
And when Mike says
something like that, you're in.
Now finish that treatment.
I will.
What was it called?
-Proud Wizards.
-[Pipo] You're grinning from ear to ear.
Hey, what… What have you heard?
-What's up?
-[Paz] What is it?
-What?
What is it?
Did you find out?
-[grunts]
-Wait. Finally.
-Yes, Uncle.
-Oh, my God, yes! The States!
-The suspense. Now I wanna know.
-[Pipo] Congrats! Oh, my God!
She got accepted
for a screenwriting fellowship.
A very prestigious one.
It's a really big one.
-Congratulations!
-All right!
-I'm so happy for you.
-Thank you.
What, you're leaving?
For where?
Brooklyn.
Oh, New York.
How'd you get that?
An agent friend told me about it
so I applied for it, and I got in.
It's pretty clear
where you got your talent.
That's amazing.
When do you leave?
[both] Next month.
Uh…
I'm really proud of her.
She worked hard for this,
and she's very humble about it.
Whose child are…
-Uh, you're asking…
-Aunt, he's a friend of mine.
-Uh, a friend.
-Ah.
And what job do you do?
I'm a psychiatrist.
Psychiatrist.
[Stella] Ah. You're a doctor?
Yes. Yes, I am focusing
on psychosomatic psychiatry.
[Tita Abby] Very fancy.
Hey, come and have dinner with us, Tito!
Eat something before you drink too much.
-Come in, Tito.
-… is that my uncle?
He hasn't changed at all.
-Hi.
-…the pity.
-Hi!
-[Tito] Hello.
Are you good?
-[Tita Abby] Oh, Lord.
-What's this?
Lechon.
It's full of fat. Eat lots of it.
Maybe you'll die fast.
-[Stella laughs]
-You're sweet.
-This man.
-[Tito] It's good. Have some.
[Tita Abby] Stop leaning on me.
I hate that
That wasn't as big before.
Before?
-You never came here to visit Papa.
-[Pipo] Oh, come on.
You didn't have enough room
for both of us.
-You're an idiot, you know?
-Look who's talking.
Hey, psst, enough already.
Your father was a good person.
-That'll do.
-That's true.
Your dad was really good
to the chicks. [grunts]
[laughs] Right?
-Hey, I won't hear any of this!
-[Tito] Yes, sir.
-What?
-What? What is it?
Papa was a depressed man.
He wasn't depressed.
The doctors just made that up.
[Migs] Uh, sorry.
Depression is actually
a medical condition,
believe it or not.
It's a mental disorder.
Migs.
-[mouthing]
-That's bullshit.
It didn't exist before.
[chuckles] Well, the good news is that
our holy prayers can fix everything.
-That's right. Correct.
-All we need to do is just pray.
Now there are faith healers
everywhere you look,
[chuckling] using herbs to clear the head.
[all chuckling]
Isn't that right?
-Praying can be beneficial.
-Uh-huh.
Usually, anxiety and depression
are natural responses
to life's circumstances.
You know, when you lose your job,
or when you're grieving,
or sometimes, when a loved one goes away.
And you're right.
Prayer can be a source of hope.
-Mmm.
-…yeah.
However, there are some times,
even when you pray, that the heaviness
and the pain doesn't go away.
Or worse, the more you live with it,
the heaviness increases
and you can't deal with it anymore.
[Tita Abby] Mmm.
When that happens,
that means it's too big.
-Ohh.
-That's when you see a specialist.
That's what you're good at, Doctor.
Selling drugs.
Happiness isn't so hard.
-[Rene laughs]
-Have a beer, right, Rene?
Buddy?
Singing karaoke,
cockfighting, cards. Yes.
There's lots of ways
to be merry. Lots.
But if someone's gone completely crazy,
put them in the nuthouse.
[laughs]
[coughs]
Uncle, drink. Drink some water.
[Tita Abby] Don't throw up here!
Hey, hey! Don't throw up here!
This is exactly why people
take their own lives.
Among other things.
-[Tita Abby] Go outside!
-Stop it, Matti.
[Tita Abby] Outside now!
-Get your act together.
-I will. Don't you worry.
There you go.
-That's why you need faith.
-[Stella laughs]
I dedicate this song
to all the women I've loved before.
I think you need to get your son examined.
[Paz] Oh, my goodness, Aunt,
I hear all kinds of noises
when he is on his own day and night,
not to mention that he paces
all the time. Plays music loudly.
I'm tired and I'm exhausted.
What are you telling her for?
Oh, I was just telling her
that you're an artist like me.
Oh, come on. Just for once,
be honest with them.
Tell them your son is depressed,
bipolar, manic depressive.
Why are you so ashamed of me?
And tell them that you hear voices.
And you have flashes of horrible memories
and you feel abandoned by your dad,
and can't calm down
without your fucking weed or your Xanax.
-Just let it out just a minute.
-He's just created this out of nothing.
This kid lies a lot.
Imagine, I've had to put up
with this for 20 years!
Do you have any idea if he's…
Can you shut the fuck up?
Ah!
You wanna know where my father is?
I can't tell you where my father is.
I have no idea.
Maybe he's in jail,
or maybe he's dead, or drunk somewhere.
Or worse, with a happy family.
He doesn't acknowledge that I exist.
And my mom just eats all that shit up
because she's being paid handsomely.
And at whose expense? Mine!
[grunting]
Any more questions?
You son of a bitch!
Huh? You're a fucking ass!
After all I've been through for you,
this is what I get?
You don't understand a fucking thing,
you ungrateful piece of shit.
How do you think we managed
to make it through day by day
if I didn't eat shit for you?
That was all for you, Matti.
Huh? Where would you be without me?
And you want to go back to America? Huh?
Go ahead! See if you'll be able
to live for just…
You can't even fucking swim!
Do you have to talk to him that way?
Oh! Here we are!
Going through the laundry basket. Oh.
Don't leave… Stay.
I don't want you to miss a thing.
That's what you're all here for, right?
To chew on every bit of shit.
Hey, Aunt Abby.
Do you really want to know
why I came back? Huh?
You can't wait to hear.
Fuck this. Goddamn it!
What did she go and do that for?
[sighs]
I have cancer.
I've come home to die.
Ugh.
[sighs]
Lighter, please.
Want to smoke?
It's okay.
That was a crazy scene you made in there.
I didn't start it.
How long have you known?
About a year now.
And what stage?
-End stage.
-What?
Chemo?
-Are you considering chemo?
-[sighs]
I tried it.
It just makes me feel sicker. Hmm?
But this, oh,
makes me feel better.
[Stella laughs, sighs]
You're going to outlast me again,
aren't you, you witch?
[both chuckle]
Paz.
I hope you know that I sincerely,
genuinely look up to you.
Ugh. You make me sound old. Stop that.
I'm serious, though.
Look at you.
You go for what you want.
No apologies. Without caring
what other people think.
I wish I could be like that--
Hey, wait. You're living your dream.
Me? Look at me.
I'm a sick old lady dying of cancer.
What are you talking about?
What is this?
You're making films in America.
That's every actor's dream.
I did one.
Even then I blew it.
You heard Matti.
I punched the director.
Did he harass you?
[exhales]
[groans]
Are you okay?
Hey,
Paz.
Why do bad things happen to good people?
-[laughs]
-What are you laughing about?
I never thought I'd be
hearing you talk like that.
[Paz] Wow, you're so mean.
Here, give me that.
[cell phone ringing]
[birds chirping]
[Paz] …we don't have any water.
Well, hello.
Yes, thank you.
[Paz] There's Miguel.
Hi. Good morning.
[Pipo] Here you go. This is delicious.
-[Jo] Morning.
-Morning.
No, I'm okay. Thank you.
Where did you go?
Out for a drive.
I was alone.
Did I ask you to come here, Migs?
Have some food.
No, I don't feel…
Uh, there. Thank you.
We need to visit the doctor.
Why?
Are you sick?
It's for you.
Ugh.
Don't go there, Joanne.
-I think we need to know about--
-To know about what?
-If I have longer?
-So we're fully informed.
Who's asking you?
This is my decision, right?
I'll take care of myself.
So for now, I'm just gonna sit
and wait it out until I croak.
… come on, sit down
and join us. Relax.
Why don't you want to be checked?
There's nothing to lose, right?
You as well.
You know what?
I'm sick and tired of doctors
and the smell of hospitals,
so please, huh, let me be.
How do we know you're not making this up?
Fucking unbelievable.
[Jo clears throat]
You don't believe me, huh?
You need proof?
Okay.
Here.
There's proof for you.
[Jo] Dad! Uncle, help! Hurry up!
-We're gonna take you to a doctor.
-[Paz] No, it's a bad idea.
-You're going to a doctor.
-…
-You need to see a doctor.
-[Paz] My wig! Matti! …
[Matti] I have it. I have it.
Your bag!
We can do a biopsy to confirm everything
and see if it has metastasized,
and then you can figure out
your plan of action.
The thing is, Doctor…
Ian?
I already know my plan of action.
It's my life, my decision.
Sorry, Doc.
Mom, what if something happens to you?
It's already happening, stupid.
Why don't we just trust the diagnosis
of the experts in New York?
It's right there in front of you.
Just read it.
And I'm not going to pay this woman
with a man's name
any more money
to learn something I already know.
Hey.
[Doctor] Actually, ma'am,
we have treatments here that have helped
a lot of patients like her.
-Cases of remission in the last stages--
-Ugh.
Remission, my foot. Are you stupid?
Ugh.
Ugh. And I did not leave
everything behind in New York
just to rot in a hospital like this.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Sorry, Doc.
Um…
-Doc, can I ask you…
-What is it?
How long has she got?
I don't have the whole picture,
but like I said earlier, some cases…
Based on this,
maybe three to six months.
What do we do now?
You're in the provinces, is that right?
-Mmm-hmm.
-She can go into hospice care.
I don't think we have the money.
Then you're going to
have to take care of her yourself.
The total amount's just here.
Oh.
Eat up.
Have something.
Eat.
Hmm. Hmm.
[retches]
Tissue. Tissue, please.
[Rene] Uh, drink… Drink some water.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I can't. I'm sorry.
Mattias.
What is it this time?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry,
but, Mom, you love this stuff.
Even in New York, you eat this stuff.
And it's fucking loaded
with pork fat and chemicals,
but you still eat it anyway.
When I was little,
you'd force-feed it to me,
I pretended to like it for you, so why
can't you pretend to like it for me now?
You haven't eaten in days.
And if you don't eat,
you're gonna keep getting skinnier,
and you're already super skinny,
-and you're just gonna fucking…
-Mattias.
Look at me. Look at me.
I am going to die. Huh?
[sobbing softly]
[playing tune on guitar]
[Jo] "My mother has cancer."
[Jo] Aunt, thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Don't mention it. Anytime.
Anything I can do to help.
If you need anything at all,
-just let me know, okay?
-Mmm-hmm.
You're a very good daughter.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
Why are you so kind to her?
Well, because I know she's like that.
You know, your mom,
she hasn't found life easy.
Uh…
You know, your mom and I,
we go a long way back.
So there is this one project
we did together.
We were playing go-go dancers.
We were prostitutes.
Unfortunately, we had this completely
abusive prick as our AD.
And for some reason,
every time I had a costume change,
over would come this AD into my tent.
You know what happened?
He finally groped me,
and your mom walks into my tent,
she saw it,
and of course, she picked up a chair
and threw it at the AD.
She was so livid,
her eyes, they were on fire.
So, you see, your mom,
she stands up for what's right.
And with Paz,
what she feels is what you get.
That's why she's so unpopular.
A lot of people dislike her for it.
But at least she's not plastic.
It's just her temper.
It's scary if she gets a little mad.
I hope you didn't get that from your mom.
Miguel, what's that?
Take it upstairs, will you?
-Medical supplies.
-For whom?
I got you Tramadol, morphine.
There's quite a lot of it there.
How did you get these?
The oxygen tank's upstairs.
Just in case you have trouble breathing.
I have cancer of the liver, not lungs.
Joanne.
Answer me.
How did you pay for this?
Joanne, I'm talking to you.
I'm exhausted. Please.
Please, do we have to fight
about it right now?
This is not fighting.
It's fine. It's paid for,
so everything is covered.
Did you beg for money?
Jesus Christ.
How embarrassing.
Give this back.
I'm not some charity.
Be grateful there's help around.
I did not ask for help.
You'll need it before too long.
You know what?
I'm not gonna use this shit.
Just give it back.
I don't care!
I'll deal with this.
-No, let me. I'll do it.
-It's fine.
[Migs] Let me help.
No, no, let me do it.
Leave it. It's okay.
Go on. They might leave without you.
[ship horn honks]
[Jo] Sequence 20. Legais sitting
on the bed, staring at the ceiling.
The wind outside is howling,
so there is a banging on the wall.
but the banging starts
to sound like a knocking.
She gets scared at first,
but thinks maybe it's his ghost at last,
so she slowly gets up,
-heads towards the door--
-[Matti] Boom!
-[screams]
-[laughs]
Sorry.
I just wanted to thank you.
For what?
For saving me.
I'm busy.
I'll be quiet.
So how are you holding up?
You said you'd be quiet.
What are you, um, writing?
-A movie?
-Mmm-hmm.
Nice.
So, what's your story?
-What, of the movie?
-Yeah.
[Jo] Uh…
It's about a girl
grieving the death of a beloved brother,
and she's on a quest
to speak to his ghost.
-How?
-An amulet.
It's an amulet
that gives her the power
to speak to the dead.
And then… [groans]
I'm stuck.
[Matti] Let me think.
What if
a different ghost comes instead,
bringing her to a direction
she never would have taken,
eventually leading her
to the answer. [growls softly]
Where'd you get the hair?
My dad.
Who's your dad?
Are you still studying?
-Huh?
-I mean, where'd you go to school?
I don't.
I finished 12th grade,
and Mom told me to take a break.
-And I haven't gone back since.
-[Jo] Mmm.
Why?
My moods, I guess.
Bad grades.
-Watch out!
-[screams]
[Matti laughs]
What's going on?
Nothing.
-Why do that?
-[mimicking mockingly] Why do that?
[Matti] Is it deep?
[Jo] Um, no.
I swam here all the time
when I was a little girl.
[Matti] You're still little. Come on.
Stop it.
She says you're stubborn.
Oh. I'm the stubborn one. [chuckles]
Wow.
I tried reaching out to her, you know.
I sent emails, I never got a reply.
So I eventually gave up.
Oh.
Okay, I'm good. It's all good.
[Matti giggles]
[Jo] Good Lord.
Okay, just remember,
if you're in deep water,
head first.
And after that, you do the frog kick,
you know, like that, huh?
And then you'll stay afloat.
Yeah? Come on, you'll learn.
Tanchi!
It's a swimming lesson,
so take us to the island.
You know, you're a really cool dad.
You're a crazy boy, you know that?
No, I really mean it. I think
I'm gonna call you pops from now on.
[both chuckle]
Let's go! Okay…
one, two, three!
[boat engine whirring]
[fish vocal sounds]
How's your script?
It's all right.
Writers block?
[clears throat]
I'm stuck because I don't know
how to end it.
Do you have to know the ending?
I want to know where it's going.
Well, what a corny approach.
So, writing feels like…
like a to-do list
when it's really, you know, an experience.
I don't know…
you don't have to have just one ending.
I don't know, just…
go with the flow,
and just feel every scene.
And see where it takes you.
Do you remember Nono?
Yeah.
Every night, he would put on an LP
while I put you to sleep.
I always remember that he had a laugh
like Donald Duck.
[mimics laugh]
[chuckles]
He was a brilliant, brilliant lawyer…
and also a very good writer.
If only I knew then what I know now.
You know, I could've…
he called you princess.
Do you remember that?
He must be so proud of you now, Jo.
[Matti] Come on, mom,
you're gonna love it!
Come on out!
Your son wants you to join us!
[both chuckle]
[engine whirring]
[cheerful screams]
Paz, drink something,
then you'll feel better.
Thanks.
Let's take a family picture.
Yeah, let's do it.
-Ma!
-What?
-Please take our picture. Mm-hmm.
-I just have to click it?
-You're drinking beer again?
-Just the one.
Everyone look happy, all right?
Over here!
Okay, um…
[Joe] Mom, you have to count.
Count, then click.
Okay, one, two, three, four five…
-What!
-Hey!
One, two, three… one, two, three…
-[both] click!
-There you go.
Ah! Yeah!
Smile!
One, two, three, click!
There. Beautiful. One, two, three…
[camera shutter clicks]
Oh, wonderful!
One, two, three, click!
[all laughing]
[scoffs] It really hurts.
[gasps]
Will you marry the doctor?
I can have a doctor in the house.
Ma, he's just a friend.
I'm not stupid.
Just rest please.
How did you even meet?
Are you his patient?
Busted.
[chuckles softly]
I'm not judging you, Jo.
I've fucked a few doctors in my life.
Just be careful.
[exhales]
[groans softly]
Ma?
[groaning]
Mom.
[Ben] Hey, what's wrong, Joe?
You've been hard to reach lately.
Everything all right?
I'm sorry, Ben, I've been looking after
my sick mother.
Aww, I'm sorry to hear that.
You should have said something.
You still wanna be a part of this, though?
I've worked so hard for this, Ben.
Oh…
What should I do?
I could try talking to
a few of my colleagues…
-Ben…
-Yeah?
-I'm sorry but I gotta go.
-You know what, Joe--
[Rene] Pancit, everyone!
So delicious.
There we are.
[chuckles]
Hand me that.
-[Paz] Where is it, Rene?
-Here, it's here.
-Wow, thank you.
-That's okay.
Hand it to your sister.
[Bes] Pass your plate.
-Your sister. Give it to your sister.
-Right, right.
-Your sister.
-Here it is.
Uh, no.
I'm sorry. I have to work.
Come on, Jo. For me, please.
-[Matti] It's good.
-All right.
-[Bes] This is yours.
-Thanks.
-Come on.
-[Rene] Oh, yeah.
[puffs]
[coughs, chuckles]
[Bes] Take it easy.
Hey, slow down.
It's sumptuous.
[all chuckling]
[Bes] Do it. Please.
You'll end up choaking.
Mom, how is it?
The food.
This is perfect last meal.
-What?
-[Rene] Now, this is perfect.
You never know, right?
Mom!
-Just eat up.
-Ah-ha!
You guys are so not ready for this.
Have you guys thought of the eulogies
you're gonna give when I go?
Matti boy?
Come on, pretend that it's my funeral.
-You have to say something.
-I don't wanna do that, mom.
Just try it, Matias.
Try!
-Come on, you can do this.
-All right, all right.
Everybody, thank you for coming tonight.
I'm so fucked faded right now.
[all chuckling]
Tonight, my dear mother…
is dead.
[all chuckle]
Matti, come on.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
You have to say something nice,
something like,
"My mother, she's a loving person.
-"She's hard working…"
-[all laughing]
Hey, Rene, you've been laughing
the whole time,
chuckling away, come on then.
Let's hear it.
Come on, Rene.
[all laughing]
The fuck! Come on, say it.
All right, all right…
[laughing]
Did you know, the very first time
I met Paz,
she was already a celebrity.
Always in the news,
because she was dating everyone.
Did you know that she dated a famous
well-known actor.
-Do you blame me?
-Do you remember?
He was always…
-that guy who was--
-Dammit, Rene!
This is what will remain with you
after I'm dead?
[all laughing]
God!
Insane.
You're crazy, Rene.
Hey, Joanne now.
Brilliant writer. Say something inspiring.
You know, for your mom.
Come on. Please.
-Come on. It'll be easy for you.
-No.
-Come on, guys.
You're all so…
Hey, okay, okay, let's do it this way.
Jo, take notes.
"She embraced her world fully
and lived her life fearlessly,
"but sadly life wasn't so kind to her.
"She was battered by painful experiences,
"nevertheless…
"she remained selfless and generous."
There you go.
All right, it could be different.
It could be like this. Take two.
"She embraced the world fully.
"She lived her life fiercely,
"unfortunately life wasn't so kind to her.
"And she was battered
by painful experiences.
"Nevertheless, she remained selfless
"and generous."
Not bad, huh?
Okay, Paz, our Paz…
our shining star.
Oh, that's so good.
"Our shining star
"has taken her rightful place
among the stars.
"She was not only a great actress,
"she was also a loving daughter,
"a kind sister, a loyal partner…
-"and most of all, she was…
-[Jo thuds]
Joanne, I know, you wanna say something.
-Joanne?
-No.
Okay.
"Maria Paz Del La Santos…
"a wonderful, wonderful mother."
That's it.
-Hmm?
-Bullshit.
-Did you say something?
-[slams cutlery]
If you have something to say, say it.
Come on.
-What?
-How would I know what to say,
-when you're a stranger?
-So, you're blaming me?
Who else, Ma?
Or maybe it's my fault then?
Okay, before you say anything,
I'd shut up.
You don't understand anything.
Please make me understand.
You have no idea what I went through.
How it wasn't easy…
After I gave birth to you,
I had to quit working.
I had to settle down with your father,
be a good wife, be a good mother.
I had to take care of your Nono.
I had to give up my career!
Nobody wanted to employ you, Ma.
Why can't you just accept it?
I was protecting you, Joanne.
I was protecting you.
If I hadn't left…
I could have put myself in danger,
you in danger…
And what happened?
I was still hurt by you.
And now, since you're out of money
and you're sick…
you're back for Round 2,
as if nothing ever happened.
And you expect us to drop everything.
I never asked you to take care of me!
Never!
Why did you want me to be here?
'Cause I wanted to see if you're okay
before I died.
Hmm.
To assuage your guilt,
you travelled back home
to check if the daughter you left
managed to do okay anyway.
Our your fucking sin first.
Oh, my god… Joanne.
Why do you have
so much hate in your heart?
Oh! [chuckles]
So much? Yes, Ma!
Because of how long you left me for…
not one explanation.
You left me when I was a child!
Why, Ma?
Why?
Explain to me now, what I did wrong?
-I was--
-How did I fail?
I was not well.
Not well?
Okay.
That's why you left for "America"?
To be single again? To…
find another man
and give birth to another child?
You have no right to judge me.
You have no fucking clue
what I went through in New York!
Well, you think you're…
so fucking smart!
I had to become smart.
I had to parent myself for 27 years!
You weren't there!
And yet, I made something of myself.
And you…
look at you.
Your life went nowhere.
You know, when you were gone…
I was okay.
[thunder rumbling]
Well then, good for you.
I'm so happy that you found peace
through therapy…
with…
that handsome psychiatrist you're fucking.
Well shit…
who's selfish now?
I'm putting my dreams on hold
because I wanna be here for you.
I never asked you to.
I'm not like you!
I can't just
ignore my conscience like you.
Abandoning a loved one.
Now, there it is.
You finally said it.
So the whole reason you're here,
is not for anything, but for you
to feel better about yourself.
Or, is it to show everyone
that you're so much better than
your loser mother. Is that it?
Is that your dramatic through line?
You're not any better.
You come from a long line
of narcissistic, proud people
who would gladly sweep
difficult conversations under the rug,
and pretend that everything is fine
until it's not.
And then we escape.
Because that's what we do,
you and I, both.
-Mom, please. If you'd only--
-What?
Huh? Be sorry?
[thunder rumbling]
[loud thunderclap]
[wind blowing]
Look after yourself, okay.
-[Bes] Jo, darling!.
-Mom.
You phone. [exhales]
Say goodbye to your mother.
[breath shaking]
I love you.
-Take care.
-Love you.
-Uh, hi.
-Hi, Ben.
-Jo?
-Sorry, did I wake you?
No, no. That's fine.
I just emailed the final treatment.
You did! And that's great to hear.
-Yeah, let's do this.
-Great, Jo.
Uh… you don't sound too happy though.
You okay?
-I'm just tired.
-Okay, then.
Can you make here next week,
like Tuesday?
-What do you think?
-Tuesday?
Yeah, there is a chance--
Hello?
[knock at door]
-[banging]
-Just wait.
-Hi.
-Hey.
-What? You're here!
-Yeah.
You left this.
-Oh, thank you!
-No problem.
Oh, it's just me.
I took the bus here,
And aunt Des taught me.
-See?
-Oh… okay.
-Well, I gotta go. See ya.
-Hey.
-Matti, stop. Come in.
-Really?
-Yeah!
-All right.
I'll take you to the station tomorrow.
So…
are you hungry? Have you eaten?
Come on.
I have, well…
leftover pasta and beer.
Ow, what kind of beer?
-It's just beer.
-Whatever.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
I'm leaving next week.
Already?
I was about to leave
when you guys arrived.
You excited?
Nervous.
You'll survive.
You are mom's daughter after all.
Hmm.
How's your mom?
You know…
still a…
-bitch.
-[both chuckle]
[exhales softly]
You never ran away?
-From mom?
-Hmm.
Never.
You know, even while she'd be screaming
at me,
I still felt that she loved me.
I love how we'd watch movies together,
and I'd curl up on the couch next to her…
and I even love the way she smells
like cigarettes all the time.
It's kind of weird.
You know, in New York,
we would take walks on Sundays,
and she would tell me about
the Philippines and how beautiful it was,
and yadda, yadda, yadda.
And she would tell me about
how much of herself she saw in you.
And then, she would just be quiet
for a few blocks…
and we would just walk and walk,
and she wouldn't say anything.
And I always wondered why.
Maybe she was thinking of you.
In fact, I know she was.
[traffic noise]
Hey, you don't have to wait for me.
-I won't get lost.
-Bus is leaving.
It's okay. Lemme check
if this is the right one.
[man] Come on. Get in.
-Does bus to go Lucena?
-It does, ma'am.
-Hurry up, we're about to leave.
-This is the one.
Well, I guess this is it.
Good luck in New York, and grab a slice
of pizza for me while you're there.
Okay. Sure.
Uh…
-You didn't take a shower. Gross.
-I need the instructions to get back home.
-All those to Lucena, we're leaving now.
-See ya.
Take care.
Come on. Get a seat.
[bus reversing]
[chuckles]
[soft piano music playing]
[bus honks]
Bus driver! Wait!
[music continues]
[heart beating]
[Matti playing Spanish guitar]
[birds chirping]
-Pa?
-Hmm.
There's no disguising this crack.
It's all right.
Perfection can be overrated.
Darling.
Please find it withing you
to forgive me for not opening up to you.
You should know that my family
didn't talk a lot.
To speak up was taboo.
But thing that's important…
is that I love you
more than I can possibly tell you.
It looks like you got a scratch there.
Oh, that's… [chuckles]
I got this scar when I was a child.
Forgot it was there.
Some wounds last forever.
Matti! Matti, come here!
Your mom's ready!
-Get over here!
-Coming.
[Jo] They really put here in here?
[Des] This choice was your mother's.
Okay.
-Still grumpy.
-[all chuckle]
When we get to the sea,
we'll scatter Paz's ashes,
and we all have to smiling as we do it!
Your mom wouldn't want to see us sad.
Okay.
Here we go!
Are we supposed to say a prayer
or something?
Uh… my lord,
thank you for the wind,
the rain,
and even for the storms we endure.
And for sun at daybreak, thank you.
Amen.
[all] Amen!
[Des] One, two… smile and three, go!
[coughing and laughing]
Take another one.
-Going again.
-One, two, three…
[coughing and laughing]
[all yelping joyfully]
[playful laughter]
Mama!
[all whooping]
[somber song playing]